<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Jacob&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://jacob-rc.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jacob&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 16:02:14 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jacob-rc.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AP Exams, a Memoir</title>
      <link>https://jacob-rc.github.io/posts/ap-exams-a-memoir/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 16:02:14 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacob-rc.github.io/posts/ap-exams-a-memoir/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents
Preamble What Are AP Exams? Remembrance Things I&amp;rsquo;ve Enjoyed About AP Exams Things I&amp;rsquo;ve Enjoyed Less About AP Exams Conclusion Preamble While not exactly pertaining to either business or computer science, AP exams have played a large role in my high school experience so I feel they deserve a proper discussion. The main objective of this article is to describe my thoughts as well as to give current and future ap students some food for thought, especially with how they feel about these defining high school exams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Makes Money in Card Games?</title>
      <link>https://jacob-rc.github.io/posts/who-makes-money-in-card-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 14:57:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacob-rc.github.io/posts/who-makes-money-in-card-games/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents
Preamble Essential Question Primary and Secondary Markets Primary Markets Secondary Markets Peer to Peer Transactions Peer to Institution Transactions When the Lines Begin To Blur Takeaways How do Small Card Shops Make Money? Events Individual Cards Takeaways Preamble I&amp;rsquo;ve been a competitive card game player for a long time now; about 5 years. In that time, I&amp;rsquo;ve found a love for both the game while I’m playing, but also the other parts of the ecosystem that allow a competitive card game to function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Correlation Power Analysis in PicoCTF 2023</title>
      <link>https://jacob-rc.github.io/posts/correlation-power-analysis-in-pico-ctf-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2023 19:57:03 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jacob-rc.github.io/posts/correlation-power-analysis-in-pico-ctf-2023/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents
Introduction Solving the Challenge Additional Thoughts Conclusion Introduction The hardest and also most interesting cryptography challenge of PicoCTF 2023 involved undoing AES using a side channel attack, specifically power analysis.
If I&amp;rsquo;m going to be honest, it was a pretty big surprise to see a side channel attack be the primary challenge within Pico but it was definitely a fun experience.
Solving the Challenge The core idea of correlation power analysis (CPA) is to take the non-linear part of AES, the S-box lookup and use that bit of info to extract more information about the key.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
